Full-stack web developer

Eveleigh, Romilly

Personal details

Name: Romilly Eveleigh

Email: romillysemail@gmail.com

Links:

- · Personal Website eveleigh.co
- · GitHub github.com/romillyeveleigh
- · LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/romilly-eveleigh-96699138

Profile

Experienced Freelance Web Developer with a demonstrated history of working in the marketing and digital media industry. Skilled in JavaScript, React, HTML, CSS, and full-stack development. Highly-driven IT professional with a Bachelor's Degree from the Courtauld Institute, University of London.

I started building my earliest websites whilst I was still a teenager. I've always been driven by a desire to figure out how things work and solve technical problems so coding has been the perfect match for me. My first commercial project was creating a custom database-driven e-commerce site for my employer in just a few weeks. Since then, my knowledge-base has steadily grown through a combination of self-study, persistence and practical experience.

Nowadays, I like to use React due to its active user community and excellent component libraries, but I can quickly learn whatever stack is necessary. With the right tools for the job and my adaptability, I'm confident to tackle any task.

Key skills

HTML, CSS and JavaScript (ES6). My preferred specialty is developing full-stack web apps using React (including hooks, context and Redux) and associated technologies including Express, MongoDB, Postman and Firebase. I frequently pick up any new technologies as and when necessary.

Experience

- · Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript (ES6), React
- · Operating Systems: OS, Windows
- · Database systems: Firebase (incl. Cloud Firestore, Real-time Database), MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL
- · Other: Shopify, WordPress, WooCommerce, AWS, InDesign, Photoshop

Employment history

OVCHARENKO LTD Dec 2015 - Present*

Freelance Web Developer/Editor

· Worked on a variety of commercial projects including e-commerce sites as well as providing digital content and content editing services. Recently developed a full-scale single-page web app to assist people applying for UK visas (spousevisahelper.com) which was built from scratch with the potential to be scaled up to provide SaaS as a complement to the growing online 'virtual lawyer' sector.

- The project was built on React with authentication provided by Firebase. The site utilizes a Cloud Firestore database, and draws upon libraries including Bootstrap and react-router. I make all my sites fully responsive, with user input forms, modals, custom styling and special optimizations for iOS. I have experience deploying on Heroku, GitHub and Apache servers, both for front-end static content and backend APIs. My latest project is a Twitter-inspired messaging web app.
- I also acted as a freelance editor, providing English-language support to a range of websites in the news, events and marketing industry.
- Key technologies: React, JavaScript, Firebase, HTML, CSS

REGINA LONDON Mar 2010 - Dec 2015

Project Manager

- · Worked as a project manager for an events startup. I was in charge of setting up a new London office and implementing all of the logistical and technical requirements of the business, from building databases and digital marketing, to managing subscriber email lists, maintaining a digital archive and preparing digital presentation materials for clients. I lead a team of 15+ staff, and worked on projects in cities including Berlin, New York, Moscow and Basel. I developed my skills for working on large-scale projects and ensuring that they were delivered on time, efficiently and within budget.
- Key technologies: HTML, CSS, FileMaker Pro, Photoshop, InDesign

IBID PROJECTS Sep 2006 - Nov 2009

Project Manager

- · Worked as a project manager for a London-based exhibitions and events company. I implemented all of the technical requirements of the business, including maintaining the company website, creating digital marketing content, administering network systems and maintaining a digital archive. I developed my skills for working under pressure on time-sensitive projects. I learned to use my technical knowledge to solve practical problems quickly and efficiently.
- Key technologies: HTML, CSS, FileMaker Pro, Photoshop, InDesign

May 2004 - Aug 2006

Freelance Web Developer

- Worked on building websites for local businesses and private clients. My largest project was developing a complete online e-commerce solution for a print sales business with a stock of over 10,000 items. I taught myself PHP and wrote custom scripts linking a CMS website to a MySQL backend database with data converted from FileMaker Pro. The resulting website produced a significant increase in turnover for the business upon launch. I developed my skills for producing simple-to-use, SEO-friendly, database-driven websites.
- Key technologies: HTML, PHP, CMS, FileMaker Pro, MySQL

Education

Courtauld Institute, University of London - BA History (2:1)

Interests

Motorcycling, photography (instagram.com/streetartasia), design, history, travel. For several years I worked remotely, and I lived and traveled in many countries throughout Asia and Europe before settling back in London.